Guide to the Carnegie Foundation Records, 1905-1945
Carnegie Foundation Records, 1905-1945
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carnegie Foundation records, 1905-1945
3-4-122
Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
1.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pension records, financial records, meeting minutes, pamphlets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records concerning the establishment of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, including letters from Andrew Carnegie to Jacob Gould Schurman and Livingston Farrand (Presidents of Cornell and trustees of the Foundation). The collection includes extensive correspondence of Foundation presidents Henry Pritchett, Henry Suzzallo, and Walter A. Jessup, and secretaries Clyde Furst and Howard Savage; also, material and lists pertaining to pensions, financial records, trustee meeting minutes, and published pamphlets concerning the Foundation.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records concerning the establishment of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, including letters from Andrew Carnegie to Jacob Gould Schurman and Livingston Farrand (Presidents of Cornell and trustees of the Foundation). The collection includes extensive correspondence of Foundation presidents Henry Pritchett, Henry Suzzallo, and Walter A. Jessup, and secretaries Clyde Furst and Howard Savage; also, material and lists pertaining to pensions, financial records, trustee meeting minutes, and published pamphlets concerning the Foundation.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching.; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919.; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.; Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939.; Pritchett, Henry.; Suzzallo, Henry.; Jessup, Walter A.; Furst, Clyde.; Savage, Howard.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Pensions.; Education, Higher.; College teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Available Copies:
Microfilm available.
CONTAINER LIST
- Establishment of the Carnegie Foundation. Letter from Andrew Carnegie to Jacob Gould Schurman; Clippings, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Carnegie's Announcement of Gift. Schurman's trustee correspondence., 1905-1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Carnegie's Announcement of Gift. Schurman's trustee correspondence., 1908-1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Pritchett, Carnegie, Schurman letters., 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Willcox, Pritchett letters,., 1919-1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Carnegie, Pritchett letters., 1905-1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett, Hammond letters; Cornell University., 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Teachers' Insurance and Annuities. Schurman correspondence; Cornell University report; correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett letters., 1905-1907 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett letters., 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett letters., 1909-1911 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett letters., 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett letters., 1915-1921 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Pritchett, Furst, Farrand letters., 1913-1929 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Schurman Correspondence. Salary lists of Cornell University Faculty, 1908-1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Furst letters., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Schurman, Furst, Farrand letters., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Furst, Farrand letters., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Teachers' annuities and insurance; Schurman, Furst, Pritchett letters., 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Teachers' annuities and insurance; Schurman, Pritchett letters., 1918-1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Salary lists sent to Carnegie Foundation., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- List of Pensionables., 1916-1931 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- List of Pensionables., 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Business for Meetings - Farrand Minutes. Minutes of the meetings of the Executive Committee., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Business for Meetings - Farrand Minutes. Minutes of the meetings of the Executive Committee., 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Business for Meetings - Farrand Minutes. Minutes of the meetings of the Executive Committee., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Business for Meetings - Farrand Minutes. Minutes of the meetings of the Executive Committee., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Business for Meetings - Farrand Minutes. Minutes of the meetings of the Executive Committee., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
- Minutes of the Sub-committee on Finance., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Minutes of the Sub-committee on Finance., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Savage, Farrand, Day letters., 1931-1943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Savage letters., 1930-1936 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Furst, Suzzallo letters., 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Jessup letters., 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Savage, Farrand letters; Farrand chairmanship., 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Savage letters., 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Carnegie Foundation Correspondence. Miscellaneous material., 1932-1936 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Carnegie Foundation Pamphlets, Reports, Act of Incorporation, Foundation Papers, Memoranda, Rules., 1905-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)